and S mukarji welcome back you know S I
was just thinking that with Sor mukarji
we always discuss which is a good stock
to buy which is a good company to invest
in is he there I can't see him yeah I'm
I'm here I'm here hello hello so you
know with you we always discuss which is
a good company to buy which is a good
stock to buy which is a good sector to
think my question is that Sor mukarji
has created a good franchise called
marceles investment you're managing
billions of dollars how can one invest
in s mukar I'm not going to give you
money to manage I want to best in
marceles how can that happen actually
s let me quote him verbatim because
before you came on air he was telling
me look at him he's now managing
billions of
dollars and it's the it's the faith of
the Indian investor in the country
itself that is all long talk tell me the
reason you are a smart stock
picker how can one inv s mukarji so so
Marcela stock for better of award is not
for sale at the moment maybe maybe five
six years out maybe Marcela stock might
be available to the uh to the to the
World At Large at the moment it's owned
by the employees by and large um and all
jokes apart in all seriousness whil the
the the employees own the company uh
without without uh the Indian investors
faith in the country and remember we we
through you know three three traumatic
years two years AG covid now all this
drama around Ukraine but what's
remarkable is is the sort of unrelenting
faith of the Indian investor in the
country itself fpis come and go uh the
local investors stand strong and that's
what allowed us to to build a business
where uh where we be able to uh you know
run a company with 120 people managing
13,000 crores all of that wouldn't have
been happen happening if the local jenta
the local public in India hadn't
believed in the country's economy
you we built a wonderful franchise my
friend just been such a pleasure
tracking your journey as an entrepreneur
such it's been such a pleasure
compliments sinc your compliments you
very much s have you got fresh inflows
in this market volatility I'm just
trying to gauge it because the mutual
fund folks are getting flows have you
got fresh in flows when markets fell in
March so so we were getting around 100
crores a week for most of the last
couple of years uh when the war with
Ukraine broke out for the for a couple
of weeks it reduced to 50 60 crores a
week but over the last uh 10 days or so
we're back to the usual marceles number
of around 100 crores a week coming in um
and and and as you're saying that's
consistent with what we hearing from the
mutual fund industry the the local
investor the Indian investor has been
has been Rock Solid we got uh fi flows
till June July last year our foreign
foreign client INF flows uh did dwindle
through the winter uh over the last
couple CP weeks some of our foreign
clients have been visiting India again
amongst other people they've met us and
my Reckoning is you know if the conflict
in Ukraine doesn't escalate I think
foreign inflows will also start coming
back for us and for other people uh
through the course of the
summer Amir Aurora on the channel
yesterday and he gave a very interesting
data point and I know a lot of people
come on channel and they just data sort
of this is expensive that is expensive
his data point was that in last couple
of years the profits
for Consumer companies have doubled but
the prices have tripled which is there
is a p expansion which has happened now
for the first time there is a demand
impact and there is a margin impact so
he's making a case that the P multiples
have to contract purely because of the
expansion which has happened in the past
which has been higher than the earning
expansion right so so I think the first
thing to realize is what drivve stock
prices is not earnings what Drive stock
prices is free cash flows and uh and if
you take the typical company that we
invest in whether it's a little champs
portfolios where uh last week we opened
it for inflows after two years or in our
Flagship consistent Compounders
portfolio whether it's in our small Caps
or in our large cap portfolio what we
have seen over the last two years the
last five years is profit compounding in
India in well-run companies tends to be
between 15 to 20% so if it's a larger
company like Asian pain speed toite
profit compounding is around 15% % if
it's a smaller company like say an alky
AM means or a GMM fora profit
compounding would be around 20% right
but free cash flow compounding which is
the real driver of share prices whether
it's an Asian pains or a pedite large
companies free cash flow compounding 25%
even through the last three four five
years and then the smaller stocks the
little chams franchises as we call them
free cash flow compounding is around 35%
so this difference right is big uh if a
company compounds if a company as big as
a Asian paints or a ped compounds
profits at 15 but cash flows at 25 uh
and it's the cash flow compounding which
is driving the stock optically the P
multiple will look high because the p
the p is not following e the p is
following free cash flow so if I give
you an extreme example astral poly over
the last 10 years profits are up 5x free
cash flow is up 100x share price is up
100x right and and and you know we spent
a lot of time explaining this to people
that what drives share prices is not
profits astral poly profits are up 5X in
10 years free cash flows are up 100x you
need to follow the cash not the pat
follow the cash not the Pat and you'll
make good money in India even through
the current fiscal that's going to end
today free cash flows are up very very
strongly for almost all our investi
companies good morning SAR you know
through many interviews you for example
have told us you know you have a
research meeting on Fridays uh you
analyze the BC 500 company you carry out
I think 30 40 forensic tests on them to
figure out this cash flow youve given us
one idea but tell us in recent times U
what is it that you bought in the crash
you told us earlier that you accumulated
more of Asian Paint and fidelite but
what else so so I think I think I might
might have mentioned before we've also
bought plenty of Dr L uh we couldn't
make any logical sense of the share
price pullback as we just discussed the
multiples don't drive share prices so we
bought of Dr L over the last couple of
months in our small cap portfolios uh
one area where we have to hold our hand
up and say we haven't we didn't quite
guit writers over the last uh three
years we've we've contended we in fact
told your viewers on this program that
auto and auto ancillary would do well
they haven't done well and hence over
the last couple of months we have pulled
back from our Auto and auto ancillary
Investments a lot of that money has gone
in the small cap portfolio into VM we've
been holding V for two years uh the
shares haven't done much over the last
12 months even but as the unlock
proceeds given the quality of Bart's
franchise given the way VM has crushed
working capital I think if you look look
at Indian retail barring Trent barring
Westside uh we don't see anybody else
managing the apperal business as well as
VM does so we've load loaded up further
on VM as we've reduced our Auto and auto
anity Investments and in our larger cap
portfolios we bought ICC Lombard we
bought more of ICC Lombard in our in our
Flagship portfolio consistent
Compounders so those have been the two
areas where we bought two franchises
which we had investments in the past but
we have ramped them up over the last
couple of months quite aggressively Bart
and ICI
lomard okay and so that's great to know
and uh incidentally we did have V on the
channel just yesterday but sort of the
other question for you is uh we talk in
the morning A day after access new
franchise buying out City bank's
consumer business great ads today the
city never closes having said that
access is a company which is looking at
m&as to plug holes in its franchise
right it's done it with Max life now he
doing it with city are you looking at it
what do you make of it sure so we have
access in our Kings of capital portfolio
Kings of capital is our financial only
portfolio we've uh had it for around two
years uh obviously we've had some push
back from clients over the last couple
of years as ACC hasn't had the greatest
of run but we've persevered we
persevered partly because uh we've seen
amab build a great franchise at HDFC
life we've also perceiv it because as we
do ground level checks and we have done
ground level checks right throughout
covid on
accesses Branch Network on the people
who have been joining The Firm the new
people that amav has brought in a view
has been that this man is turning around
the axis franchise he's bringing in good
people he's putting operational rigor
given that they had spare Capital given
aab trct record we we banked that he
will deliver and we're happy to see the
deal we're happy to see the City Bank
deal it will take them two three years
to actually show us the fruits of that
deal in terms of better Roes um but
given that they have Surplus Capital
what they seem to have acquired is a
profitable franchise uh we think it's
the right deal to do we're also quite
Keen to see more happening on the access
Max front where uh nobody knows banka
banka and the power of banka he's
selling insurance through the branch
networks of a high quality private
sector back I don't think I don't think
anybody understands better than amab so
we're keen to see more happening on the
axis and Max front uh overall given how
few high quality private sector Banks
there are in our country you can count
them on the fingers of one hand in fact
you don't even need the fingers of one
hand to count high quality private
sector Banks we think this is a space in
which uh a strong player like axis with
Kasa Kasa ratio now approaching 45 47%
will do very well in this in this
incipient economic
recovery right you know sort of whenever
we have you on air the amount of tweets
that we get saying that I'm we're not
interested in the icsa Lombard access
kind of IDE ideas get more like a porak
from him so I want to know what the
hidden gems are in your portfolio
anything off late no so I think we
discussed Pak we' continued building
that position U I think as as I
discussed in our last interview uh it's
a controll Market barriers to entry are
high uh whilst a couple of other larger
companies do make first Gene in India
our Reckoning is their commitment to F
Gene their capacity constraints in F
Gene are considerable and therefore this
is your only Pure Play private sector F
genene manufacturer fgen is an essential
industrial chemical as essential as
chlorine because of the balas tragedy
our countries had a mental block about
it uh it is hazardous but at the same
time it's essential and therefore we
reckon Bosak is beautifully place to
make money uh we are looking for more
small cap ideas but I I will be honest
it takes lots of hard work and it takes
one one and a half years of research to
nail down a stock which you can invest
in um given that in all our in all the
in all our stocks that we are discussing
we're committing hundreds of crores of
capital to it uh clients's money my own
money my family's money we're committing
large sums of money to it we got to be
very careful about these Investments so
in a given year you'll see us making one
or two small cap Investments and perhaps
getting out of one or two small cap
stocks so VM has been a little champ for
us Bak is now a little champ for us um
and whilst I appreciate the tweets that
you guys are getting it is hard to find
small cap ideas with you know sort of
metronomic regularity we'll try our best
but it is difficult I put that
disclaimer up
front
is but uh you know since you're talking
about your little champs I want to know
which are the little champs in the last
two years uh VMA of course is one that
you talked about but which are the other
big candidates which really made you
those um big monies in the last two
years so I think as we've discussed I
think repeatedly on your channel over
the last couple of years I think alky
amines and GMM fer we first spotted
actually first invested in them three
years ago uh but over the last couple of
years they've made our clients a lot of
money um in fact if I look at our little
champs portfolio in its entirety in two
and a half years we've more than doubled
clients's money and a significant role
was played by alky amines and GMM F more
recently a company that we get invested
in two years ago fine Organics is coming
through very nicely uh we also have high
hopes of of Galaxy surfactants um and
and if I look at the uh the financial
space avas financiers we think is a is a
lender that can make money for us um
they've done well but I think the the
real upswing in AAS given that they're
well capitalized well-run l the real
upswing in AAS will come in now that the
unlock has happened and the economy has
started recovering but I think pride of
place in terms of creating wealth for
Marcela client should go to uh alky
amines and and GMM
foder so s let's say if Asian pins and
pedite ey are large cap Champion
Compounders GMM foder and alky amine are
they in that category which is that
these are long-term long-term
Compounders so the the main difference
right I mean leaving aside obvious
difference in market cap right say the
the gmms and the alky are on10th the
market cap of a pelite or a or a nation
base leaving aside that obvious
difference the main difference tends to
be uh the instit institutionalization of
the franchise so in smaller companies uh
like GMM like alky like
Bosak like Seine Organics the dependence
on the promoter is greater whereas in
larger franchises like aan paints or a
TCS it's far more institutional right
where the fames taken a backseat and
high quality managers typically people
hired from the iits and IMS when they
are in the early 20s and then they grow
to run the business that
institutionalization is far more
advanced in our uh in our Flagship
Flagship Investments and consistent
Compounders one of the things we work on
quite closely with our small capab
Investments is is nudging them proding
them guiding them to institutionalize
the business encouraging the promoter to
play the role of a capital allocator and
handing over the Day to-day Management
of the business to to uh to high quality
managers it's it's not easy to do these
people are hard to find plus it's hard
for promoters to let go but I think that
institutionalization if you ask me is
the fundamental difference between our
little champs versus our our consistent
Compounders shift gear g s and let's
talk about a headline which in a sense
will puzzle everybody when you read a
headline like this it is a Monday
morning headline which is I'm not
talking about Ukraine don't worry it is
Global Bond deals have inverted and when
Global Bond deals have inverted it means
there is a recession coming in the world
a recession in the world is bad news for
equities now whether it is Asian paints
or pedite or whether it is Tata steel or
whether it is hindalco a recession is
bad news so when you are investing and
when the US sophisticated bond market is
telling you that a recession is coming
how does one deal with this and how
should one approach and how should
Equity investors approach it sure sure
so so just to sort of step back and
think about it right we've been
discussing a whole bunch of names over
the last 10 minutes or so if you notice
very few of them are cyclical place
right uh uh for obvious reasons
companies like like alky uh like GMM who
Supply raw materials to the
pharmaceutical industry they're not
cyclical play because the pharmaceutical
industry isn't a cyclical play but even
less obviously per apps companies like
a ped or an asan pains aren't cyclical
either so so the first thing to realize
is neither you nor I are experts in
calling the economic cycle and I've
certainly made it clear to clients from
the time we set up marcelus that don't
expect us to be timing the macro cycle
or timing a commodity cycle we have no
expertise in that I don't think anybody
does out there so so timing economic
Cycles commodity Cycles has not been uh
has not been a clever way to invest in
any country not just India and and hence
it's something we have stayed away from
doing
uh furthermore if you if you look at the
biggest challenges India has faced over
the last five years the last five years
I wouldn't say have been exactly an
economic boom in India we've had GST Co
demon um and in spite of those hits in
spite of those repeated shocks to the
economy you've had these companies uh uh
pedite a nation pains a Titan
compounding free cash flows at 25% so if
you can go through a rough economic
patch like our country has done off and
on over the last five six years and come
out with 25% free cash flow compounding
I'll happily take that and last factoid
if we look at India because we are
investing in India the job creation data
is spectacular so epfo published this
data five six days ago in the last three
years tough three tough years for India
India has created 32 million jobs in the
formal sector right he's a formal job
creation this is epfo CMI is also
validated the same data the entire
Workforce of France is 30 million the
entire Workforce of UK is 30 million
India has created as many jobs in the
last three years in the formal sector as
the entire Workforce of G7 countries
that gives you a sense of the robustness
the resilience of our country which is
why I'm not going to lose too much sleep
about the inversion of the yeld curve in
in the United
States because if there is a bare Market
coming technically I'm just trying to
understand the cycle part of s and I'm
glad we having this conversation it's
more like a macro conversation uh when
you see a recession or a bare Market
coming a 25 to 30% fall even more can
easily happen because Equity also has
this inherent nature which is called
mean reversion so what you're trying to
understand from you perhaps is that look
your approach towards individual stocks
is great but if it's a rising tide which
takes everything higher a receding tide
will bring things
down so so uh in part I sort of semi
acknowledged your Point by saying uh uh
uh five minutes back that auto and auto
ancillary we have ramped off our uh we
have ramped off our investments we
reduced our Auto and auto anary
Investments perhaps uh we didn't quite
think of it in in macro terms when we
did so nun but perhaps uh are pulling
back on our Auto and auto an
reinvestments perhaps as an
acknowledgement that that uh that the uh
from a Global Perspective perhaps not
from an Indian perspective from a Global
Perspective the the best of the economic
expansion is done but at the same time I
would urge you to think about the fact
that if you if if I look at our own
client base the biggest fear is is
interest rate hikes right the there this
constant sort of fear that interest
rates and if interest rates hike
there'll be some pull back in the market
so it's very very paradoxical on the one
hand uh uh uh uh the American Market is
worried about a recession on the other
hand the Indian market is worried about
higher rates and obviously there's a
contradiction there uh the Federal
Reserve is unlikely to pump rates higher
and push America into recession
uh um and at the same time uh of these
two of the higher interest rates or a
recession I don't think both will kick
in together I think we'll get a mixture
of the Federal Reserve nudging rates up
by say 100 bips or so over the next 12
months and at the same time the
overheated economic recovery that we
have seen in the west where American
economic growth is running at some four
and a half 5% and a giant IT services
company like Accenture is poting 28% uh
Revenue growth is unbelievable the rate
at which America is growing I think we
will see a cooling off of the frenetic
economic recovery in the western world
and we will get some degree of
normalization in interest rates after
covid both of those are I think healthy
Corrections healthy normalizations in
the postco world neither of those those
I think should be used by uh people who
are watching this to do tactical
positioning of the portfolios because I
don't think that sort of investing works
so I'll partly concede the fact that the
economic recovery in the west should
slow down it's been overheated and uh
the fed has made it abundantly clear
that there's a rate hike coming so both
of those take us to some degree of
normality as we return to a to to normal
circumstances after covid as best as we
can given the whole Ukraine
scenario that's s Muki there for you
with the the mind of a test player
playing sometimes 2020 Cricket right
that's what he wrote in his book thanks
a lot SAR for joining us live today on
the market it's always great having your
views um